Nick Bolles

https://www.NickBolles.com | www.LinkedIn.com/in/NickBolles https://Gitlab.Dev.NickBolles.com | www. Github.com/NickBolles

10210 Rustling Birch Rd. Apt 221 Verona, WI 53593 (715) 781-5549 me@NickBolles.com

About Me

Hey! I'm Nick! I love development, business philosophy, and discovering new technologies. I have experience with a wide array of technologies, with a passion for web development and emerging technologies. I take an iterative approach to development by emphasizing clean code, unit testing, CI/CD, open source and standards-based technology. I also have a business focused mindset; I enjoy brainstorming ways to solve business challenges with technology solutions to achieve efficient, effective, and low cost results. I spend my free time doing hobby development, focusing on the javascript ecosystem and learning new technology. I have developed a few large apps, mostly for learning purposes and they are available on my Gitlab server. Check my website for more info and links to my LinkedIn, Github and the Gitlab server that I run. For all code examples check my gitlab server.

Some of my Skills

- Strong understanding of business and how technology can influence day-to-day business operations
- Strong knowledge of the software development process and how aspects affect business outcomes
- Excellent development skills including: Typescript/ESNext, Angular (1.x and 2+), React, Vue, SASS/CSS, NodeJS, Feathersjs, MongoDB, GraphQL, .Net, REST, Design patterns, Database design, and more
- Extensive experience with software development tools and methods such as Git, SVN, Docker, Jasmine, Mocha, Github/Gitlab, Gitlab CI/CD, Jira, NPM, Webpack, Gulp, Cordova, Balsamiq, Agile, Scrum etc.

Experience

Epic, Verona WI - *Software Developer*

June 2017 - Present

- Full stack developer (MUMPS, .Net, Typescript) responsible for project design, development, and testing
- Application point person for several areas, such as performance testing and training tools
- Learn to formulate viable solutions to complex challenges that large software companies struggle with
- Assisted in establishing new area of ownership for complex and company-wide integrated functionality
- Designed and developed batch edit tool to save thousands of hours a year across the healthcare industry
 - Effectively organize designs and project timeline to accommodate for challenges encountered
 - Established robust guardrails & error management processes to further reduce management time
 - Develop frontend to efficiently show progress and a massive amount of results with great UX

Epic, Verona WI - Software Developer Intern

May 2016 - August 2016

- Designed and developed a mobile IOS app in Swift
- Effectively communicated with end users and mentors to incorporate feedback into design
- Implemented a working prototype and presented to peers and division leaders

Geodigital, Mendota Heights, MN - Software Developer Intern

May 2014 - January 2016

- Completed a self driven project to develop a dynamic documentation system for web services
- Only summer intern to secure a position beyond the scheduled internship end date of August 2014
- Develop numerous javascript features to enhance .Net web app
- Worked with Delphi, SQL, JQuery, .Net

Education

University of Wisconsin - Whitewater - Double Major

September 2013 - May 2017

- Bachelor of Business Administration in Information Technology Emphasis on Business Analysis
- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science